Guide to the John W. Gardner Papers SC0908
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John W. Gardner papers
1912-2004
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Gardner, John W. (John William)
SC0908
154.25 Linear Feet
Collection includes speeches and writings by, as well as articles about Gardner; correspondence, awards and honors, photographs, audiovisual material, and files from many of Gardner's organizations including Common Cause, the White House Fellows, the Haas Center for Public Service, and the John W. Gardner Center. Collection also contains biographical files and material from memorial services held throughout the nation for Gardner. Notes and materials related to the PBS documentary John Gardner: Uncommon American are also included.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
John Gardner earned his B.A. and M.A. in Psychology from Stanford University and his Ph.D. in Psychology from the University of California, Berkeley. Gardner served as the Secretary of Health, Education, and Welfare under President Lyndon Johnson from 1965-1968. He founded the citizen's advocacy group Common Cause and was the chairman of the Commission on White House Fellowships. Gardner served on the Stanford University Board of Trustees from 1968 to 1982. He was a founding member of the national advisory board of the Haas Center for Public Service and remained active with the center. In 1989, Gardner was named the first Miriam and Peter Haas Centennial Professor in Public Service. He was a consulting professor in the School of Education at the time of his death in 2002.
Description of the Collection
Collection includes speeches and writings by, as well as articles about Gardner; correspondence, awards and honors, photographs, audiovisual material, and files from many of Gardner's organizations including Common Cause, the White House Fellows, the Haas Center for Public Service, and the John W. Gardner Center. Collection also contains biographical files and material from memorial services held throughout the nation for Gardner. Notes and materials related to the PBS documentary John Gardner: Uncommon American are also included.
Gardner, John W. (John William); Stanford University. Graduate School of Education; Stanford University. Haas Center for Public Service; Common Cause (U.S.); Gardner, John W. (John William); President's Commission on White House Fellowships (U.S.)
- Papers, Accesion ARCH-2002-140
  - Kellogg Leadership Studies Project, 1995-1996 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Kellogg Leadership Studies Project, 1995-1996 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Joint Venture Silicon Valley, 1997-2001 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Joint Venture Silicon Valley, 1997-2001 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Entrepreneur's Foundation, 1998-2002 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Entrepreneur's Foundation, 1998-2002 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Entrepreneur's Foundation, 1998-2002 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - American Leadership Forum, 1991-2001 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - American Leadership Forum, 1991-2001 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 1 of 9) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 2 of 9) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 3 of 9) (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 4 of 9) (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 5 of 9) (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 6 of 9) (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 7 of 9) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 8 of 9) (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Civic Ventures, 1996-2001 (folder 9 of 9) (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Democracy 21, 1997-2001 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Democracy 21, 1997-2001 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Democracy 21, 1997-2001 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Community Foundation Silicon Valley, 1994-1999 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Community Foundation Silicon Valley, 1994-1999 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Community Foundation Silicon Valley, 1994-1999 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Collaborative Economics Alliance for Regional Leadership, 1997-2001 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Collaborative Economics Alliance for Regional Leadership, 1997-2001 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Collaborative Economics Alliance for Regional Leadership, 1997-2001 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR) Bohrnstedt-Gilmartin, 1991-1993 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR) Reports [bound]
    - Understanding Community, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Building Capacity for Neighborhood Community, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Development of Community-Building Tools for Congregations, 1996 (Box 6)
    - Measuring Workplace Community: Final Report, 1996 (Box 6)
    - The Status of Community in the JCFRC: A Summary Report, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Building Community in the Workplace, 1993 (Box 6)
    - Measuring Workplace Community, 1993 (Box 6)
    - St. Lawrence Academy, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Understanding Community, 1992 (Box 6)
    - Status Report: XYZ Corporation, 1994 (Box 6)
    - Status Report: XYZ Corporation, 1995 (Box 6)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 1 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 2 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 3 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 4 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 5 of 6) (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR), 1991-2000 (folder 6 of 6) (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Affordable Housing (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Aging (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Campaign Finance Reform (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Character Education (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Children – Families, Schools (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Children – Families, Schools (folder 2 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Cities (folder 1 of 2) (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Cities (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Civic Journalism (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Child Act-Hatch/Kennedy (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Community Policing (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Conflict Resolutions (folder 1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Conflict Resolutions (folder 2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Electronic Communities (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Keppel (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - The Fifties (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Forums-Mathews (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Jobs (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Neighborhoods (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Performance Measures (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Regional Issues (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Department of Justice Memo-Black Power, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Social Entrepreneurship (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - States (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Campus Compact Dinner-St. Francis Yacht Club, 1998 Feb. 10 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Larger Community Foundations-Phoenix, AZ, 1998 Jan. 29-31 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - San Francisco Foundation-U.C. Berkeley, 1998 September 28 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - New Orleans-Golden Key Award, 1995 Feb. 9 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Emerging Issues-North Carolina Washington, D.C., 1995 Feb. 14 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - National Civic League-Washington, D.C., 1995 Feb. 22-25 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Coalition of Community Foundations for Youth-Kansas City, 1995 Apr. (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - San Diego Healthcare Forum, 1995 Apr. 25 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - White House Fellows Reunion, Washington, D.C., 1995 May 2-7 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Detroit, 1995 Jun. 12-13 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Cleveland, 1995 Jun. 22-25 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Snowmass-Aspen, 1995 Aug. 2-6 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Hilton-Nevada, 1995 Aug. 17 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Kellog-Kauffman Seminar-Aspen, 1995 Sep. 10-14 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - National Civic League-Denver, 1995 Oct. 5-8 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Independent Sector-Boston, 1995 Oct. 20-25 (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Saybrook-Rollo, 1995 May 10-17 (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Business Enterprise Trust-New York, 1995 Nov. 13-14 (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Leadership U.S.A.-Pomona, 1995 Nov. 17-18 (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - MacArthur Roundtable-Chicago, 1995 Dec. 6-10 (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Carnegie-New York, 1994 Jan. 11-15 (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - National Civic League-Philadelphia, 1994 Feb. 10-12 (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Kauffman Foundation-Independent Sector-Washington, D.C., 1994 Mar. 14-18 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Commonwealth Fund-New York, 1994 Apr. 4-6 (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Clinton Meeting on Nonprofit Sector, 1994 Apr. 11-13 (Box 10, Folder 27)
  - Social Venture Network-San Diego, 1994 Apr. 14-15 (Box 10, Folder 28)
  - National Civic League-Washington, D.C., 1994 May 4-7 (Box 10, Folder 29)
  - Mike Walsh Memorial Service-Houston, 1994 May 10 (Box 10, Folder 30)
  - National Civic League-San Antonio, 1994 May 19-20 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Leadership Center of Greater St. Louis, 1994 May 31-Jun. 4 (Box 10, Folder 32)
  - Federal Quality Institute, 1994 Jul. 13 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Kellogg-Kauffman Seminar-Aspen, 1994 Jul. 24-28 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Communitarian Network-Los Angeles, 1994 Aug. 5-7 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Aspen Institute Distinguished Fellows Meeting (Cancelled), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Aspen-Bruce Murray, 1994 Aug. 27 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Washington, D.C., 1994 Sept.7-9 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - International City/County Management Association and National Civic League Chicago/Washington, D.C., 1994 Sept. 21 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - NEH-Washington, D.C., 1994 Sept. 27-30 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Independent Sector-15th Anniversary Chicago (Cancelled), 1994 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - National Civic League-Philadelphia, Kansas City, D.C., 1994 Nov. 10-13 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Independent Sector-New York (Cancelled), 1993 Jan. 4-6 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Leadership Florida-Orlando, 1993 Feb. 12-13 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Forum Club-Houston, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Aspen Planning Meeting-Kansas City, 1993 Feb. 23-24 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Hawaii Executive Conference, 1993 Mar. 30 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Indianapolis-Washington, D.C., 1993 Apr. 12-15 (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Kansas City, 1993 Apr. 25-28 (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Chicago, 1993 May 2-5 (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - Trimble Graduation-Ontario, 1993 May 15-16 (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - Kauffman Foundation-Kansas City, 1993 Jun. 1-3 (Box 11, Folder 20)
  - Leadership Florida Points of Light-Orlando, 1993 Jun. 10-13 (Box 11, Folder 21)
  - Santa Fe, 1993 Jun. 18 (Box 11, Folder 22)
  - Communitarian Network-Washington, D.C., 1993 Jun. 29-Jul. 1 (Box 11, Folder 23)
  - National Institute for Dispute Resolution, Washington, D.C., 1993 Jul. 15-18 (Box 11, Folder 24)
  - Kellogg-Kauffman-Michigan, 1993 Jul. 24-28 (Box 11, Folder 25)
  - Aspen, 1993 Aug. 11-15 (Box 11, Folder 26)
  - Kauffman Foundation-Kansas City, 1993 Sep. 13-15 (Box 11, Folder 27)
  - Independent Sector-New York, 1993 Sep. 21-23 (Box 11, Folder 28)
  - Independent Sector-San Francisco, 1993 Oct. 17-19 (Box 11, Folder 29)
  - Washington, D.C., 1993 Nov. 1-6 (Box 11, Folder 30)
  - Midwest Center for Nonprofit Leadership, 1993 Nov. 10-14 (Box 11, Folder 31)
  - Cummings Foundation-New York, 1993 Dec. 8-10 (Box 11, Folder 32)
  - Independent Sector-Washington, D.C., 1992 Jan. 7-8 (Box 11, Folder 33)
  - Irvine-Pasadena, 1992 Mar. 27-29 (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - Points of Light-Chicago, 1992 Jun. 23-24 (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - Aspen Institute-Distinguished Fellows, 1992 Aug. 20-25 (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - Dinner with Gardner Fellows-Independent Sector Board Meeting-Washington, D.C. New York, 1992 Apr. 7-8 (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - Drucker Foundation-Ontario, CA, 1992 Apr. 27-28 (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - Revson-New York, 1992 Jun. 8-10 (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - Aspen, 1992 Jul. 5-9 (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - Independent Sector-Washington, D.C., 1992 Sep. 15-17 (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - Independent Sector-Minneapolis, 1992 Oct. 25-30 (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - Council of Michigan Foundations, 1992 Nov. 5 (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - American Public Health Association-Washington, D.C., 1992 Nov. 8-10 (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1992 Nov. 13-14 (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - Lady Bird Johnson's 80th Birthday-Austin, 1992 Dec. 4-5 (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - Carnegie-Washington, D.C., 1992 Dec. 9-11 (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - Community, May 1991 (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - National Academy of Public Administration, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Drucker Article, November 1995 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Common Cause, 1991-1999 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Common Cause, 1991-1999 (folder 2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Common Cause, 1991-1999 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 1 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 2 of 7) (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 3 of 7) (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 4 of 7) (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 5 of 7) (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 6 of 7) (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Correspondence Memos, 1994-1997 (folder 7 of 7) (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - National Civic League Alliance for National Renewal-Rosters, undated and 1994 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - National Commission on Civic Renewal-Meeting Transcripts, 1997-1998 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - National Commission on Civic Renewal-A Nation of Spectators, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - National Commission on Civic Renewal-Correspondence Reports, 1997-2000 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Independent Sector-Board of Directors Meeting Agendas, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Independent Sector-Publications and Conference Agendas, 1980-2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-2001 (folder 1 of 5) (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-2001 (folder 2 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-2001 (folder 3 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-2001 (folder 4 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Independent Sector, 1985-2001 (folder 5 of 5) (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Higher Education Act of 1965: Public Law 89-329-Hon. John W. Gardner: Secretary of Health, Education and Welfare-Reports, Bills, Debate and Act, 1965 (Box 15)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2004-188
  Conditions Governing Access note
  Restricted - Single Folder in SC Restricted Boxes in GW403
  - Organization Files:
    - General Service Foundation, 1989-1999 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Girl Scouts of the USA – National President's Advisory Council, 1985-1997 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Greater Kansas City Community Foundation, 1994-1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Organizations – H, 1992-2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Evelyn and Walter Haas Fund, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Walter and Elise Haas Fund, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Harvard University, 1997-1999 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Hewlett Foundation, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Organizations – I, 1997-2000 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Indiana University – Center on Philanthropy, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - International House of Japan, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Interphil, 1987-1993 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Institute for the Future, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Institute for Global Ethics, 1990-2001 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Institute of Medicine, 1996-1997 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Irvine Foundation, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Organizations – J, 1992-1999 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Johnson Foundation – Racine, 1983-1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Robert Wood Johnson Foundation, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Joyce Foundation – D.Leff, 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Organizations – K, 1992-2001 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Kellogg-Kauffman Seminar, 1993-1999 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Kettering Foundation, 1992-2001 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Kids Voting, 1995-1997 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Knight Ridder, 1989-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Organizations – L, 1997-2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Leadership Florida R.Glass, 1992-1997 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Leadership USA, 1994-1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Learning to Lead, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Legacy Awards, 1995-2001 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1990-2001 (1 of 2) (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - MacArthur Foundation, 1990-2001 (2 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Polsby Advisory Council, 1989-1997 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Positive Coaching Alliance, 1998-2000 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Pres. Coun. On Sustainable Development, 1997 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - President's Summit for America's Future, 1996-1997 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Presidio Council, 1991-1995 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Public Agenda Foundation, 1995-2001 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Public Innovator, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Public Policy Institute, 1996-2001 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Public/Private Ventures, 1997-1999 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Punahou School, 1998-2001 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Coalition of Community Foundations for Youth, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Mayfair Initiative, 1997-2000 (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Mayfair Initiative, 1997-2000 (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Mega-Cities, 1990-1996 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Meridian Institute, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Modern Maturity Magazine, 1997-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Mid Peninsula Hospice Foundation, 1992-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Monnet Council, 1989-1993 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Organizations – N, 1991-2001 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - National Academy of Education, 1978-2001 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - NAFTA, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - NAPA [National Academy of Public Administration], 1984-2001 (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - National Academy of Sciences, 1984-1999 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - National Association of Regional Councils, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - National Board of Professional Teaching Standards, 1997-1999 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - National Commission on the Public Service, 1987-1990 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - National Conference for Community and Justice, 1998-2001 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - NIDR, 1994-1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - National Issues Forums, 1997-2001 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Friend of National Public Radio, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - National Urban Coalition (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - New American Revolution, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - New Leaders Press, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - New York Academy of Medicine (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Organizations – O, 1997-2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Packard Foundation, 1996-2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Panetta Institute, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Partners in School Innovation, 1998-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Peninsula Community Foundation, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Peninsula Habitat for Humanity (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Tom Peters Fund, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Pew Charitable Trusts, 1994-1999 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Pew Center for Civic Journalism – Ed Fouhy, 1994-1996 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - The Pew Forum on Education Reform, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Pew Civic Entrepreneur Initiative, 1994-2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Pilgrims of the U.S.A., 1997-2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - The Planetary Society, 1980-1997 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Organizations – P, 1997-2000 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Points of Light – Schubert, 1989-2001 (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Points of Light – Schubert, 1989-2001 (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Quest Scholars, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Organizations – R, 1990-2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - Responsive Community Editorial Board, 1990-1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - Rheedlen Centers Geoff Canada, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Organizations – S, 1997-2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - San Francisco Foundation, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - San Jose Mercury News, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Eric Schaps Developmental Studies Center, 1988-1997 (1 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Eric Schaps Developmental Studies Center, 1988-1997 (2 of 2) (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Sigma Beta Delta, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Ed Skloot – Surdna, 1994-1996 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Social Venture Network (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Southport Institute for Policy Analysis (SIPA) Advisory Council, 1987 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - State of the World Forum, 1997-1999 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Summerbridge, 1992-1993 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Organizations – T, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Teach for America, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - TechnoServe, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - Twenty-First Century Initiative, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - Organizations – U, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - University of California, Berkeley, 1987-1995 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Organizations – V, 1998-2001 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - Volcker Commission, 1989 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Volunteers in Asia Adv. Council, 1991-1993 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Organizations – W, 1994-2001 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Western Journal of Medicine, 1992-1998 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - White House Fellows Foundation, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - White House Millennium Project, 1998 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - World Business Academy, 1996-2000 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - World Futures Society, 1981-2001 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Youth Venture, 2000-2001 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Youth Build, 1999-2000 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Files:
    - A 1995-2001 (Box 11, Folder 18)
    - Adams, Bruce 1997-2001 (1 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 19)
    - Adams, Bruce 1997-1998 (2 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - Adams, Bruce 1984-1998 (3 of 3) (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Adler, Richard 1999 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Walter Truett 1993-2000 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Ashford, Robert 1997-2000 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - B 1999-2000 (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - B 1989-1999 (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Babb, Richard 1993-1996 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Barnes, Craig 1973-1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Barzun, Jacques 1999-2000 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Bandura, Al 1996-2001 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Batten, Jim 1989-1998 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Beck, Lowell 1976-2000 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Bennis, Warren 1987-2000 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Benton, Majorie 2000-2001 (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - Berger, Renee 1991-1996 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Berkley, Bert 1993-2000 (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Bing, Peter 1971-1998 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Blackwell, Angela 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Bok, Derek Sissela 1991-2000 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Bookbinder, Hyman 1969-1991 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Borling, John L. 1989-1999 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Bortz, Walter 1996-2001 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Bowen, William 1972-2000 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Boyd, Alan S. 1970-1992 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Boyer, Ernest 1983-1995 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Boyte, Harry 1989-1998 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Brademas, John 1970-1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Bradley, Bill 1995-2000 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bray, Charles 1975-1995 (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Bray, Sharon 1999-2001 (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Bronte, Lydia 1989-1994 (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Brown, Dyke 1995 (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Bryant, Anne 1995 (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Bundy, McGeorge 1970-1988 (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Burns, James MacGregor 1984-1996 (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Burtch, Bruce 1999 (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - C 1997-2001 (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - C 1992-1997 (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Califano, Joseph A. Jr. 1972-2001 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Campbell, Tom 1989-1998 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Capen, Dick, 1991-2000 (Box 14, Folder 5)